Lord Van!
Please wake up.
What's the matter?
It's still early.
It's urgent!
Sir Dee and Sir Esparda
are already hurrying to the site.
The site?
The lake you created behind
the village the other day.
Lake Van.
Huh?
Wait, "Lake Van"?
How'd it get that name?
The villagers named it that to honor
your deeds for generations to come.
By the way, they're thinking what
to call the village, and Van Village—
Stop.
That sounds all kinds of bad.
Our lord has arrived.
Lord Van.
What is it?
Well...
Huh? What the...
EASYGOING TERRITORY DEFENSE
BY THE OPTIMISTIC LORD
EPISODE 5: A RARE SPECIES'
PASSIONATE ENGAGEMENT COMPETITION
She's an apkallu.
They are half-human, half-fish.
An apkallu?
Yes.
They're reputed to live in
picturesque rivers in deep forests,
but for some reason, a number
are here in this lake you made.
They're a rare species
that few ever encounter.
I see.
Um, excuse me. Did you need something?
Uh... What's your name?
Can she understand what I'm saying?
Till, Khamsin, could you bring some meat?
Sure.
Have some if you like.
Offering food is a good way
to demonstrate friendship.
Here she comes.
I can eat this?
Yeah.
This meat...
It's armored lizard meat.
If you'd like more tomorrow,
I can make some jerky.
Who defeated the armored lizards?
Oh, that would be—
Lord Van did.
Lord Van's strength made it happen.
It was Lord Van!
No, no, it was thanks to all of you.
I see.
What was that about?
Think she'll be back?
Their species is rarely sighted.
She likely won't return for some time.
Stands to reason.
THE NEXT DAY
What is this?
Oh, it's that girl.
You're right. The one who asked us
who'd defeated the armored lizards.
The apkallu don't view armored lizards
as gods or something, do they?
I've never heard of such a belief.
Then...
I would like to speak with the young man.
S-Sure.
That's one scary look. What does he want?
Thank you for being kind to my daughter.
Your daughter?
Oh, you mean...
Young man, I hear you're the one
who defeated the armored lizards.
It appears that's what
everyone has agreed on.
No way!
This young child?
You're kidding!
Is he a powerful mage?
Although I didn't defeat them on my own—
Hero, you have my permission.
You may marry my daughter, Lada Priora.
Huh?
M-Marry?!
Does the arrangement dissatisfy you?
I am Ladavesta, and Lada Priora
is my only daughter.
When she grows up, her beauty will
shine as bright as any precious gem.
But...
Lada Priora is still a child.
I don't think she understands
what you're suggesting.
Why are you offering her hand in marriage?
Is there a reason behind it?
Until now, my people have
avoided making ties with humans,
but in recent years, armored lizards
have encroached on our rivers,
and many of our number have been lost.
That is why I seek someone strong
to become Lada Priora's husband.
I wish to secure a place
for us to live in peace.
In other words, he's offering up
his daughter as a bride
in order to forge an alliance
with a powerful human.
In that case, the marriage
part is unnecessary.
Please allow your daughter to marry
whomever she chooses in the future.
You're refusing?
I'll protect your tribe,
regardless of any marriage.
You sincerely mean that?
Of course.
Then, we shall settle here.
Well, since that's settled,
let's get building.
What incredible magic.
It's a rest area.
Everyone can use it at their leisure.
It's very spacious and seems
like a nice, relaxing place.
You'll be safe in here even
when it's gusty and rainy.
I'm glad everyone's enjoying themselves.
Lord Van. It's nearly time
to deal with the sewage.
Oh, that's right.
What are you going to do?
Well, you see, I've placed sewer pipes
underneath the buildings in the village.
We regularly send water from the moat
down them to flush away all the sewage.
Otherwise, it'd get unsanitary.
I see. Then, let us help you.
Huh? You don't mind?
We excel at working in the water.
Thank you so much.
Okay, we're opening it now.
That went well, thanks to your help.
Do you do that every day?
Yes. Several times a day, in fact.
I see.
Then, allow us to take on the task
of handling this "sewage."
You mean it?
Consider it thanks
for letting us live here.
That'd be a huge help.
Oh, Lord Van.
There you are.
What are you up—
What? Those are apkallu!
I've never seen one before.
Son-in-law, you have my gratitude
for your kind welcome.
S-Son-in-law?
Surely not. You married an apkallu?
Uh, no, I haven't—
Yup, I'm Van's wife.
Van is my husband.
Lada Priora?!
See you later, husband.
Lady Arte, sorry for calling you
out here so early.
I just thought it might be nice
to take in the morning air on the lake.
I-It's fine. I like taking in the
morning air, too. It's very refreshing.
I'm glad to hear it.
Um, about that apkallu from yesterday...
I heard the story from Panamera.
It sounds like we both misunderstood.
Th-That's right.
I'm sorry for jumping to conclusions.
I'm happy that's ironed out.
You built this lake and developed
the village so much. You're incredible.
Not at all. It was all thanks
to everyone else helping me.
Good morning, husband.
Lada Priora?
Who are you?
Huh? My name is Arte.
Uh, we were just having
a private conversation—
Oh, hey! It's the meat man!
Don't call him that. He's the lord.
Good morning.
Lord!
Meat man!
Hey, that's dangerous.
Lord!
Husband, are you all right?
"Husband"?
I explained to your father
that we're not engaged.
He just bullied Lada Priora.
Huh?
Uh, wait...
Everyone, rock the boat!
Yay!
I'll give you some meat, so just stop!
Hooray!
This is scary!
Meat, please.
Seriously, stop it!
We love Van!
Scary. Too scary.
Son-in-law. Lada Priora
told me all about it.
You were flirting with another woman
when you already have my daughter?
Huh? You mean me?
Well, first of all, I'm not her husband—
We will hold a competition.
Huh?
You will compete against my people,
and if we win, you will officially
recognize your betrothal to my daughter.
Huh?
We accept your challenge!
Dee?
Leave it to me, the Chivalric Order's
deputy commander. I'll bring you victory!
Settling this quickly might let you
focus more on your studies, it's true.
Oh? This sounds interesting, Lord Van.
But if I lose—
It's all right.
You'd never lose, Lord Van.
You two are too biased toward me.
Then, shall we settle this
with a three-round competition?
Very well.
You may choose the nature of
the first contest, son-in-law.
Hm, what should it be?
So if you land this ball in your
opponent's zone, you score a point.
I've never seen nor heard
of such a sport.
Wow, Lord Van. You know something
even Sir Esparda doesn't.
What incredible knowledge.
I mean, it's just volleyball.
That aside, these swimsuits you made
for us are very comfortable.
Aw, yeah.
Lady Panamera is what
every woman aspires to be.
You're joining our side?
Of course.
I need Lord Van to get engaged
to Lady Arte, after all.
Right, Lady Arte?
Good luck, you two!
You can do it!
Thanks!
Okay. Bring it!
Huh? They might be too good at this.
We're getting crushed.
This is impossible.
Is that the extent of your passion?
If you give up, it's game over.
But the tears spring forth.
I'm a girl, after all.
Fight on!
It's futile! Take this!
I'll make sure to keep it alive!
I'll place everyone's hopes
into this ball!
And I'll score!
We did it!
Nice smash.
Okay, the real match starts now.
Right!
Here I go!
There!
Weak!
We clawed them back. It's now level.
It's match point.
The next one to score wins.
Have this!
Got it!
This is the end!
I won't let you!
Good.
We won.
We'll have to start over from nothing.
Right.
There's some sports anime
happening over here.
Now then, son-in-law.
We will decide on the next event.
Sure. What will it be?
Swimming.
Swimming?
The contest will be a two-person relay.
This is bad. If we lose one more event,
I have to marry Lada Priora.
But the apkallu are master swimmers.
Leave it to me.
Dee? Can you swim?
Of course!
Then, I'll join him.
You, too, Khamsin? Will you be okay?
Yes. I'll give my all for your sake.
Ready.
Ah! She's fast from the very start!
If their lead grows any bigger,
we're done for.
Khamsin caught up to her!
What tenacity.
You can do it, Khamsin!
Daughter, hurry!
Good.
I'll take it from here.
You did well.
Now, leave it to me!
Why the butterfly stroke?
Sir Dee is at his fastest
when he swims like that.
That stroke lets him use
his steel-like muscles to the fullest.
H-How is that man doing that?
We won!
You did it!
You're kidding me.
Isn't that Dee's?
Lord Van, I did it!
I cannot believe we lost at swimming.
However, there is still one event left.
Son-in-law, decide on the final event.
Um...
What is this?
Pluriel, could I ask you
to produce some ice?
Sure.
Thank you very much.
There we go.
Ta-da.
Whoa.
So, what are we doing with this?
It's a shaved ice speed-eating contest.
We'll compete in teams of two. I'll take
part this time, so I'll need a teammate.
W-Would it be all right
for me to participate?
Did I make these too big?
Lady Arte, are you really doing this?
It's not too late to trade places.
I-I'll be okay.
Then, let's begin.
Ready!
My head...
It stings!
This is for my daughter.
I can't afford to lose!
Y-Yeah.
W-We might be done for.
Lady Arte! Don't force yourself!
Wow, Lord Van's incredible!
Lady Arte is, too.
We won't lose!
Yeah!
Who will win?
Thank you very much!
Lord Van's team wins!
We lost.
It was a good competition.
Indeed.
Now we can stop all this talk
of marrying Lada Priora.
I've taken an even greater liking
to you, son-in-law.
You truly are a man
worthy of my daughter.
Huh? Then, what was
the point of winning?
Continue to take good care
of my daughter.
Farewell, "son-in-law."
No way.
Lord Van?
What's the matter?
M-My stomach hurts from
eating too much shaved ice.
Oh, my. That's terrible.
You worked hard out there.
I'm glad you won, though.
That was a good competition.
You did well, too, Lady Arte.
Th-Thanks.
Lord Van is always surrounded
by lots of smiling faces.
How do I get to enjoy that?
Can I make that happen for me, too?
Since the day I was born, my father was
always busy, so I barely ever saw him.
My mother handed me off to my wet nurse
and showed no interest in me.
There was a simple reason
for that: I was a failure.
I was quite timid and picky,
plus I was no good at studying.
I didn't excel at anything,
save perhaps for my marionette magic.
Using my dolls as puppets, I found I could
move them more freely than my own body.
So I thought I might be able
to delight my mother with it.
You bring me such grief!
That was when I first learned
marionette magic is considered evil
and abhorred among the nobility.
After that day,
no one spoke to me at all,
and I became someone everyone ignored.
Then, when I turned ten,
my father informed me I would
be getting engaged to someone.
I was filled with anxiety.
But Lord Van was very kind to me.
Then, I learned that Lord Van's aptitude
wasn't for elemental magic,
but for production magic
which others considered unfortunate.
Yet Lord Van was brimming
with confidence and talent,
and he made use of
his gifts with optimism.
Perhaps if I hadn't stopped
practicing my magic after that day...
I think I'm going to try
a little harder, too.
We'll build more ramparts with an eye
toward the village's future development.
Please take the utmost care
to work safely and avoid injuries.
Yes, sir.
By the way, since tomorrow's a day off,
we'll be hosting a big barbecue tonight.
Let's all work hard until then.
Yeah!
All right!
Let's do this!
Barbecue!
That was an interesting way
to motivate them.
Sorry that it's kind of lax.
It's always like this.
Lord Van.
G-Good morning.
Good morning, Lady Arte.
I-It looks like we'll have
good weather all day today.
Did something happen? You seem
more energetic than usual today.
Y-Yes. I'm feeling
very energetic today. So...
What is it?
Even if it's just a tiny glimpse,
I want to see things
the way Lord Van sees them.
I want to get closer to that.
Would it be all right
if I watched you work?
Yes, of course.
Boss!
TRANSLATION: JOHN PICKETT
TIMING: ANDY ELLIS
EDITING: SMR
QUALITY CONTROL: RILEY DALTON
TRANSLATION CHECK: REI MIYASAKA
NEXT EPISODE: SLAYING A DANGEROUS
FOREST DRAGON WITH LARGE BALLISTAE